Once there was a way To get back homeward
曾经有休路，可以回家
Are the stars out tonight?
夜空星光燥灿…
For you
只有你
And I will sing a lullaby
我要为你唱首抠篮曲
With a song in my heart
唱出我内心的衷曲
Tell me something good
说说甜言蜜语
Tell me that you love me
跟我说你过我
Tell me, baby
跟我说，裤有具
Tell me something good
说说甜言蜜语
Only you
唯有你…
But how can you know for sure?
可是要怎么确定呢?
fs there really just one?
一人只有一首心曲邑?
f need your love
童年曼波 下 G戴利配音
Where is the love?
爱在何方?
You don’t have to be beautiful
你不一定要很印才能迷个我
i just need your body, baby
我只要你的肉朵，裤中
Hello
哈吐…
-From dusk till dawn -Is it me you're looking for?
从清晨到黄属
You don't need experience
你不必身经百战…
Take
收下…
-To turn me out -These broken wings
才能迷查我
You just leave it all up to me
把一切交给我就好
Let's talk about eggs, baby Let's talk about you and me
跟我榴党吧，裤中 谈谈人和我
You don’t have to be cool To rule my world
你不必要酶，就能反有我
Ain't no particular song i'm more compatible with
我不需要特别合我意的情歌
{just want your extra--
只要给我多…
Boys. Boys.
大彩儿…给她个机会嘛
Well, since my baby left me
自从宝贝郊并我
! found a new place to dwell
我找到新地方窟
it's down at the end of Lonely Street At Heartbreak Hotel
就在寂寞大街意头的心碎旅店
And I! said, "I'm feelin’ so lonely, baby
我好寂寞，裤由，我好寂寞
! could die
我快活不下去
Don't have to be rich to be my girl
你不必有钱，才是我的人
Don't have to be cool to rule my world
你不必要酶，就能反有我
You're the particular song i'm compatible with
我不需要特别合我意的情歌
{just want your
只要给我…多点时间
-And your kiss
和你的吻
His mom and dad met in the usual way.
他的父母就这广认识了
The song became love...
天雷义动了地火
...and love became the egg.
产下了党的结晶
Memphis?
曼菲斯，你可以吧?
Safe and warm.
当然了，温暖又安全
Whoa, I think I felt a move in there.
它好像在踢那
And in the usual way...
按照企鸣传统
...the moms left for the fishing season...
企约妈姻要离家出外捕急
...while the dads stayed home to do egg time.
企约爸爸留在家里孵蛋
You gonna be okay, Daddy?
你不会有事吧 ?
Oh, sure, honey. We'll be waiting for you, tight here on Lonely Street.
当然，我们会在我宣大街等回来
f love you more and more, tell me why
我好爱好爱你哦
Bye-bye, now.
拜拜
Goodbye, Norma Jean. Don’t you worry about a thing.
再见，诺斑珍，炼不用担心
Don't wanna let you go
我不想郊开你
i never can say goodbye, boy
我不会说再见
When all others leave...
当她们出海后
...we remain!
我们留守…
When the sun vanishes...
当太阳消失和后
Heed the wisdoms, brothers! Make a huddle!
按照惯例，弟兄们，图在一起
-Share the cold! -Share the cold.
-共同舍寒
Each must take his turn against the icy blast...
大家输流抵抽刺明的狂风暴雪
...if we are to survive the endless night.
才能燕过永无止另的寒夜
Raise your voices, brothers!
大声唱出来吧，弟兄们
Give praise to the Great 'Guin...
议颂伟大的企鸟歌神
...who puts songs in our hearts and fish in our bellies!
赐给我们心曲，让我们有急吃
Oh, baby, I think 1 wanna dance now.
宝上只，好想和共舞
No, no, no.
不…不…
There is a wisdom, brothers and sisters...
各位兄弟姊妹，有一项多蛋守则…
...that stands above all others.
绝对不能违背
-Never, ever... -It's okay.
-绝不可以… -没事了
-...n0 matter what... -No harm done. See?
-扰论如何 -还好，没有破挤
...drop your egg.
千万不能并掉你的蛋
No, we're cool. We're cool.
我们没事，没事了
Of the many thousands who sang through that long night of winter...
漫长的冬夜，成千上菌焦企镶吟唱
..it was Memphis who cried out most fervently...
只有曼菲斯唱得最热切
...to turn the Earth and bring back the sun.
呼唤太阳回到南极大地
-It’s a boy! -Hey, it’s a girl!
-是个带把的 -是女儿惠
-Come here, son. -Come to Daddy, there you go.
-过来，儿子 -过来老爸这里
Son, you have made your daddy so proud.
儿子，你真是老爸的本向
Memphis?
曼菲斯
Is everything okay?
一切都还好吧?
I don’t know. I can’t hear anything.
我不知道，一点动静都没有
-ls it empty? -Honey.
-是空包蛋 -不要乱襄
-Can I have it? -Gloria.
-可以给我唉? -葛莉亚!
It’s okay, Maurice.
没关俐，英里斯
It happens sometimes, Memphis.
曼菲斯，人这种情形常有
Yeah.
是啊
Wait, you hear that?
你匠见没有?了
-Yeah. -Hey, I can hear you, buddy.
-区见了 -我聊见了小子
Oh, your papa’s here, it's okay.
钨和爸在这里，不要怕
Oh, he’s okay, Maurice. Whoa, there it is!
他没事，英里斯，他出来了
That's his little foot there.
小脚伸出来了
There's his other one.
另一焦也伸出来了
That's different.
他有点不同
Hey! Come back here, Mr. Mumble.
回来这里，小波波
Gloria....
萝莉亚…
She can call him whatever the heck she likes.
她想叫他什么都可以
Whoa, little Mumble.
小波波
-Mumble? Mumble? -You okay?
-波波… -你没事吧?
Oh, you'll get used to it.
避惯就好了
Come on. Come to your daddy.
来，儿子，钨和爸抱抱
-What do you make of that? -Little wobbly in the knees.
-那是怎庆回事? -小脚了了动个不停
-ls he okay? -I don’t know.
-他没问题吧? -不知道
What you doing there, boy?
你在干嘛，儿子?
I'm happy, Pa.
我好快乐哦，和爸爸
What you doing with your feet?
你的肢怎庆停不下来?
They're happy too.
它们也很快乐
-l wouldn’t do that around folks, son. -Why not?
-有别人在别这样，和孩子 -为什么 ?
-Well, it just ain’t penguin, okay? -Okay.
-因为这样不像企鸣，好吗? -好吧
Yeah. Hey, come on over here. Get under here. Get warm.
好，过来，来下面取暖
Watch the beak. Watch the beak-- Beak!
小心尖中'， 别惟到我
The beak.
痛死了
Okay, good boy.
好了，矢儿子
So late. What's keeping them?
她们加到了“，怎床回事?
Pray, brothers, the Great ‘Guin does not test us with a lean season.
祈社吧“，弟兄们 伟大歌神不会用饥饿考验咱们
Why, Noah? Have we not all been dutiful?
为什么 ? 我们不金意责吗?9
So when you see your mama....
等你看到了妈旭
-l stand perfectly still. -You got it.
-我要马上立刻站好 -答对了
But how will I know which one’s my mama?
可是我怎么知道谁是我杂姻?
Oh, you'll know.
你会知道的
She's got a wiggle in her walk and a giggle in her talk.
她走路好娜多委 说话轻柔忱耳
And when she sings, it darn near breaks your heart.
唱起歌来…让你如病如酬
Hey, wait. 1 see them. I see them!
等等，我看到她们了…
You're right! You're right!
是真的…
Wives, ho!
老婆，辛著了
Wait, no. Wait, no, Mumble, get back here. No, Mumble! Get back-- Mumble!
等等，波波，回来，儿子
Mumble! Mumble!
波波 !波波!
-Roxanne? -Michelle?
-洛克珊? -蜜零儿?
-Maurice! -Michelle! Michelle!
-莫里斯 -密零儿 ! 密雪儿，…
Mommy!
-妈妈! -噢，她好可爱
Excuse me. Pardon me, pardon me. Mumble? Mumble?
对不起，借通，波波?
-Mama? -Mumble!
-媚妈? -波波?
Mumble!
波波 !
Mama? Mama?
妈妈?妈妈?
-Mumble, boy, where are you? -Mama!
-波波，你在哪里?了 一妈妈… ，
Memphis?
曼菲斯9?
Oh, Mama. Oh, Mama.
哦，孩子的旭
-Oh, my. -Daddy.
一天啊 -孩子的爸
So where's the baby?
我们的儿子呢?
Well, honey, I'll find him.
亲党的，我会找到他的
-You lost the baby? Memphis! -It's okay.
-你把儿子弄委了? -没事的
-Mama? Mama? -Stay!
一妈妈… ， -待在那里
-Come to Mommy. -No, Mumble.
-到妈杂这外来 -等等，波波
Mama, Mama.
妈妈、杂杂…
Hey, what's wrong with his feet?
他的脚怎厅了?
Oh, that’s just a little thing he’s got going. He'll grow out of it.
只是小毛病，长大了就会好
Mama!
妈妈!
Oh, Memphis, he’s gorgeous.
曼菲斯，他好可爱哦
-Isn’t he, though? -Look at you.
-可不是吧? -看看你
I got something for you.
我有永西要送你哦
Open up.
哎张开
Oh, I love the way she does that.
我最党看你全食的样子了
Good morning, class.
小朋友们，早安
Good morning, Miss Viola.
早安，薇拉老师
Right.
很好
Well, today we begin with the most important lesson you will ever learn...
今天要上的课 是你们在企灼小学…
..at Penguin Elementary.
最重要的一堂课
Does anyone know what that is?
有人知道是什么课吗?
Anyone? Anyone?
谁知道?9
Someone? Seymour?
谁知道 ? 西摩?
-Fishing? -No.
-捕急吗? -不对
Mumble?
波波
Don't eat yellow snow?
不要吃黄色的雪?
No, that’s not it, no.
不对，也不是这个
-It’s our Heartsong, Miss. -Thank you, Gloria. Excellent, yes.
-唱我们的心曲，老师 -谢谢你，葛莉亚，答对了
Without our Heartsong, we can't be truly penguin, can we?
不会唱歌，就不是真正的企先
No.
没错
But, my dears, it’s not something that I can actually teach you.
可是老师没办法教你们唱
Does anybody know why? Anyone? Anyone?
有人知道原因吗? 谁知道9
You can't teach it to us, ma’am...
你不能教我们唱
...because we have to find our Heartsongs all by ourselves.
是因为我们要靠自己找到心曲
Well done, you.
说得好
It's the voice you hear inside...
去匠心里的声音
..-who you truly are.
认识真正的自己
Yes. Thank you, Gloria. Excellent, lovely, thank you.
对，谢谢你，葛莉亚，太棒了
So let's all be very still now.
大家都安静下来
Take a moment and let it come to you.
好好想一想，自然地唱出来
-l got one! -Pick me!
-我想到了 -挑我!
-Pick me! Pick me! -One at a time. Yes, Seymour.
-挑我、挑我… -一个一个来，西摩
Don't push me ‘Cause I am close to the edge
不要吉我，因为我就快要崩溃
I'm trying not to lose my head
我不想要失去我的理智
Yes, I like that one. I could really get jiggy with that. Lovely.
好棒哦，匠得我好想跳舞
I'm ready. I got one.
我想到一首歌了
Oh, I thought you might, Gloria.
萝莉亚，那就快唱吧
Midnight creeps so slowly
黑夜缓名进带
Into hearts of those
遥向需求无度，永不满足的人
Daylight deals a bad hand
白韦的赌局
To a penguin
下注太高的企瘤一手烟牌
That's as far as I got so far.
我只想到这四名而已
-Oh, yes, lovely. Really lovely. -That’s beautiful.
-很好区，唱得真好 -好好区呈
Well, Mumble, since you seem so keen to share.
波波，你想唱就大声唱吧
Mine’s sort of a boom and a:
我想到的是本的一声，然后…
And another boom.
然后再一声
You heard that in there?
那是你想到的吗?
-Do you like it? -I’m afraid that’s not a tune.
-和喜欢吗? -那不是一段旋律
-It’s not? -No, dear. A tune is like:
-不是吗? -一般族律是…
Oh, okay.
好吧
Who is that?
那是谁呵?
That is the offspring of Memphis and Norma Jean.
曼菲斯和谐现珍的儿子
The wee hippity-hopper.
脚动个不停的那个
It’s not funny!
这不好笑啦
No. No, not in the least.
对，一点都不好笑
A penguin without a Heartsong is hardly a penguin at all.
没有心曲的企秽根本不算企鸟
I think he broke my ear.
我的耳条被你震鄞了啦
In all my years, I've never, I mean--
这刻多年来 我还没册过这广可怕的声音
And you having such fine voices. Well, it’s bizarre.
你们的歌声那记美，这就怪了
Did anything happen, you know, during early development?
孵蛋期间有没有发生什么事?
No, all fine. Normal incubation.
没有，很好啊，一切都很正常
-Right. -Wasn't it, honey?
一 对 可可 -对叶，老公?
Yeah. Yeah, it was a tough winter, I guess.
对，除了今年冬天特别冷
Right, right.
是，是
-He did hatch a little late-- -Yes, l understand. Yes.
-他是有点太了晚破珊 -我知道
-To think he might spend his life alone... -Quite, quite.
-他有可能会单身一昔子 -没错
...never to meet his one true love.
永下找不到他的真党
Oh, please, Miss Viola, isn't there something we can do?
拜旗，蔽拉老师，他还有救吗?
Well, there is always Mrs. Astrakhan.
去找天后艾缘卓就没错了
Mrs. Astrakhan?
天后艾缘齐?
If anyone can, Mrs. Astrakhan can.
只有她才救得了波波
Can't sing?
不会唱歌?
Can't sing? Rubbish, darling.
不会唱歌?不可能
Every little penguin has a song.
每售小企奖都会唱歌
When I have finished...
上完我的课
... your singing will be giving everyone the goose pimple.
你的歌声会让大家起芍皮疙将
Now, to begin. First, we must find a feeling.
区好了，一开始要先找到感觉
Happy feeling, sad feeling.
快乐的感赏、悲伤的感觉
Maybe lonely feeling.
稚寞的感觉也可以
You feel it?
有感觉吗?
Good. Now, let it out.
很好，唱出来吧
Be spontaneous.
顺其自然
That, what is that?
你在做什么 ?
I'm being spontan-you-us.
顺其自然呀
Darling, you want to meet beautiful girl?
你想认识小美眉吗?
You want to make the egg?
想生小孩吗?
Oh, yes.
想啊
Well, sing! And no jiggy-jog. Do not move muscle.
那就唱歌，脚不要乱支 一根筋都别支
No moving!
不准支 !
Twinkle, twinkle, little star
一冈一内亮晶晶
Enough!
钓了!
Okay. We go back to the top.
金了，我们再从头开始
Forget body. Look inside soul.
身硒别动，探索你的心才
Feel the feeling. Enormous feeling.
用心去感觉，强烈的感觉
So enormous it fills whole body.
全身都感动菌分
It must escape or you explode.
一定要唱出来，不然会爆炸
-Now, open your little beak. -Come on.
-现在张天你的小踢 -快点
Yes, yes. Lift up the head, that’s it.
很好，抬起头来，很好
Now.... Now....
唱啊…唱啊…
Disaster! Catastrophe!
太可怕了，太丽怖了
I never fail before.
我从来没有失败过，和从来没有 !
Never! Never!
从没有 ! 从来没有 !
-Well, 1 thought it was kind of cute. -But it just ain't penguin, okay?
-我党得他满可过的啊 -可是一点都不像企味
So what if he’s a little different? l always kind of liked different.
他有点不同又怎麻样 ? 我还满喜欢与界不同的
He’s not different. He’s a regular emperor penguin.
他不是不同，他是普通的帝王企物
Hey, you know what? I can leave school.
我可以不要去学校
Il can go to work. The three of us.
我可以去工作，我们一起工作
Whoa, little fella. You ain’t going nowhere till you got yourself an education.
小像伙，不叭书你什么也不能做
You get them singing muscles big and strong, you got that?
一定要学会唱出心曲， 明白吗?
Vil try, Pa.
我会努力的，钨爸
You bet you will. The word "triumph" starts with "try," and it ends with...?
你一定会，只有努力才能成功 努力要怎样?
-"Umph." -That’s right. A great big "umph.”
-用力 -没错，大大的用力
I'm going fishing.
我要去捕急了
Oh, Mumble.
噢，波波
That first hard summer...
他度过的第一个夏天
..-While his mom and dad were working overtime...
当和爸爸妈杂在广间的大海…
...on the great commute to the sea...
加班工作，努力养家
...Mumble found a place away from disapproving eyes...
波波找到下元大家的地方
..-where a funky little fella could be himself.
让他可以尽量做他喜欢做的事
Hey, what you doing there, flipper bird?
你在做什么，小小高?
Nothing. What are you doing?
没做什么，你又在做什么 ?
Nothing. Just dropped in for a little lunch.
没什么，只是来吃午餐
There's food? Here?
这里有食物吗 ?
Leg or wing?
先从腿还是翅膀开始吃?
Oh, no, no, wait. Not me, I'm a penguin.
不对，我是一售企义
Exactly. The flipper birds, that’s you, eat the fish.
没错 小小高，就是你，你吃急
The flying birds, that’s me, eat the flipper bird and the fish.
悉天大胸，就是我 专门吃小小高和急
And lately, there ain't a lot of fish.
最近海里没什么急…
-So.... -This time I’m getting the juicy bits.
-所以… -今天我有肥肉可吃了
-Me first! -Hey, you want a piece of me?
-我先啦 ! -滚天，臭尿蛋
Hey, hey, hey! I'm trying to think about lunch.
不要打援我吃大餐
Wait! Watch this!
等等，你们看哦
Yeah, that’s weird, all right. Listen. For once, we're gonna do this civilized.
真是个怪胎，匠好 这一次我要文明一点
-Now, get in line-- -Hey! What's that on your leg?
-排好队… -你脚上是什么东东?
-What? This little thing? -Oh, no. Don’t start him on that.
-什么 ? 这小玩意? -拜旗，千万不要问他
Shut up! The little flipper bird asked me a perceptive question.
闭跑，小小锅问我一个重要问题
-A question like that deserves an answer. -Here we go.
-我必须好好回答他才行 -又来了
I got two words for you:
四个字的答案
“Alien abduction.”
“外星怪客^
-Oh, you had to ask. -Have mercy.
-你干嘛问啦? -有点同情心
Quiet!
半踢 !
Now, little buddy, there is something out there.
小兄弟，外面有一种东西
Creatures. Not like us.
跟我们不同的生物
Bigger, fiercer, and smarter too.
比我们更大、更凶猛、更隐明
-Ask me how I know. -How?
-问我怎庆会知道 -怎庆会知道?
Because I've been captured by them, that’s how.
因为我被他们提过
Unbelievable.
不可思议
What do you mean “unbelievable?” It’s true.
什么不可思议，是真的
I'm sitting on a rock, minding my own business...
我在岩石上并关没事干
...when suddenly, they're onto me.
他们突然攻击我
These beings, like big ugly penguins.
他们就像又大又梗的企闵
Fat, flabby faces with front-ways eyes...
肥肥多肉的脸，了眼睛接在一起
..no feathers, no beaks, and these-- These appendages.
没羽毛、没类跑，膛有…四售肝
They probe me. They tie me up. They strap me down.
他们戳我、绑我、把我气平
They take this pointy thing and they stick it into me.
用尖尖的东西刺我的身体
And then, blackout.
然后我就可个
Gosh.
天啊
l woke up and there’s this-- This thing on me.
我一醒来这东西就套在脚上
Every flying bird is dissing me, “Hey, what's happening, yellow leg?”
每售屡饥都在笑我说 “你怎庆了，小黄脚?3
It was humiliating.
真是丢脸
And then what?
然后吓?
What more do you want?
脸都丢光了“，还会怎样?
They could have eated you.
他们大可以吃掉你
Yeah. Yeah.
对，没错
I guess my pitiful cries for mercy appealed to their better nature.
可能是我的哀叫引起他们的同情
Can I appeal to your better nature?
我能引起你的同情吗?
Nice try, kid, but no.
很隐明嘛，可是…做和
No. No. No!
不， 不要…'
What you doing down there, flipper bird?
你在下面干嘛，小小高?
Get up here.
快上来
Get back up here this minute.
快给我上来
Oh, great. You let him get away. Didn't you?
这下好了“，你让他跑了
All your screwy alien talk.
谁叫你又说外星怪客的事
-Hey, I’m an abductee. -Abduct this.
-我被绑架耶 -绑架个头
-Don’t make me call Uncle Angie. -Oh, fine.
-别遥我找安朱叔哦 -随便
Where youse going? I'm an abductee!
你们去哪 ? 我被绑架通那
-I don’t care what you are, I'm hungry! -Would you like to hear our specials?
-我才不管你呈，我饿了 -想知道今天的特餐是什么吗 ?
How about fish? There’s no fish. How about penguin? There’s no penguin.
来点急如何? 没有急 企钨怎庆样 ? 企听跑了
What are we gonna eat?!
咱们要吃什么?
There's a world where I can go
我可以去个地方
And tell my secrets to
诉说我的秘密
in my room
在我的房间
Paying no mind to his dancing heart...
他强忍著跳舞的签望
...the kid saw out his school days at the back of the class...
站在教室最和后面度过童年时光
...lost in his imaginings.
成天胡思乱想
Now it's dark and I'm--
天色展暗，和孤单一人
What fabulous worlds lay out there, far beyond the ice?
冰天才地之外有什么美禁世界 ?
Was there any place...
有没有地方…
.-.-where one small penguin without a Heartsong...
让没心曲的小企狼
...could ever truly belong?
找到心起的色属 ?
in my room
在我的房间
And so, a thousand generations ago...
在一千个世代以前
...our forefathers forsook our wings for flippers.
我们的祖先收起羽相游向大海
You graduates going to sea for the first time...
你们这些娃业生将第一区下水
...are to reap the benefits of their wise choice.
享受祖先明智决定带来的恩泽
These are lean and uncertain times.
这是个圣辛的急冬年代
But by the power of the ancient penguin wisdoms...
但是壮著伟大祖先的智慧
...we, my brethren, will endure.
我们帝王企鸟必将繁盛半大
-"Blah, blah, blah.” -Norma Jean.
-他真是有金唾唆
Who is he to say my boy can’t graduate? He’s not hurting anyone.
我儿子为什么不能杂业 ? 他又没有伤害别人
--true to our ways and you will always be worthy of this...
只要坚守规拭就能捍本传统
...our brave penguin nation. Excelsior!
祝大扰居的企钨帝国永世昌盛
Ocean, here I come!
海洋，我来了 !
You know what? We're gonna have a little graduation ceremony of our own.
让我们举行自己的小小兴业典礼
-You mean it, Ma? -You betcha.
-妈，真的吗? -当然了
-Excelsior!£
-永世昌盛
Keep it down.
小声点
-Pa. -Memphis.
-和爸 -曼菲斯
-Go get them, tiger. -Thanks, Ma.
-让他们看看你的属守 -谢了，媚
-Make every moment count! -Got you, Ma!
-要把握每一刻哦 -我会的，旭
-Remember, "Stranger Danger.” -Yeah, sure, Pa.
-别忘了，椒徐陌生人 -没问题啦，苑
And watch out for those leopard seals and them killer whales.
小心豹斑海豹还有虎鲸
Mark this, Noah.
记住，详哈
Guys!
大彩儿
Wait up!
等等我
What do you think?
你觉得怎样了
-You first. -No, you first.
-你先跳 -不，你先跳
No. No, no, no.
不，不要
Stop pushing!
不要推啦
-What was that? -l think it was the fuzzball.
-那是什么 ? -好像是那个小毛球
See any blood?
有看到血吗?
What you waiting for?
你们在等什么?
Hey, Gloria!
，葛痢亚
Gloria, I adore-ia. I'd like to see more-ia.
我喜欢你，我想每天见到你
Gloria.
萝莉亚
-Mumble? -Gloria.
-波波? -葛莉亚?
I'm sorry. I didn’t mean to....
对不起，我不是故意…
Fall back, coming through!
借过一下…我来嗓
Gloria? All my life, I've wanted to say that you're so--
葛莉亚，我从小就想说你好…
-Fish. -Yeah. You're so fish.
一介 -对，真的好急
No. Fish!
不是啦，有刍 !
Fish!
急来了 !
Oh, that’s mine.
那是我的
-That’s lousy. -You didn’t get one?
-太惨了 -你没抓到?
Sorry.
不好意思
Gloria. You got one?
萝莉亚，提到没有?
-Nope. Not this time. -You have it.
-没，这次没有
-Thank you, Mumble, but it’s yours. -l want you to have it.
-谢了，不过那是你的 -我想要给称
-No. You caught it. You eat it. -l want you to--
-不，你提到的你吃 -我棣吃…
Skua! You get back here!
且鸥，你给我回来
-Come on. -Mumble! Let go!
-快点 -波波，放并
Mumble! Let go!
波波，快放开
You just let him get away!
你让他逃走了
-ls he breathing? -He’s certainly not eating.
-他还有呼吸吧? -他肯定没在吃急
Mumble? Are you okay?
波波，你没事吧?
Mumble?
波波?
Take the fish.
把急吃掉
-What? -Take the stupid fish.
-什么? -快把这休笨急吃掉
Oh, okay.
好吧
Thank you, Mumble.
谢谢你，波波
You're welcome.
不客气
On this, our night of graduation, infatuation, illumination...
在举业这一晚，请欢迎迷合囚生…
...top of the class, Missy Gloria.
歌声美妙的模范生葛莉亚小姐
Each morning I get up, { die a little
每天早上香沉沉
Can barely stand on my feet
站都站不稳
Take a look in the mirror and cry a little
看著镜中的自己及泣
Lord, what you doing to me?
主啊，你把我怎么了
! spent all my years in believing you
这刻多年来，我深信著你
f just can't get no relief, Lord
件得不到解腕，主啊
-Somebody
有谁啊
Oh, f try and { try and I try
我努力努力又努力
But everybody wants to put me down
可是每个人都在看我
They say, they say, I'm going crazy
他们说我疯掉了
They say { got a lot of water in my brain
他们说我满胶的村糊
Got no common sense ! got nobody left to believe in
没有常识，没有人可以相信
What’s wrong with you?
你是怎庆了?
-Mumble. -Yeah?
-波波，你最好… 一怎样?
-You listen. You know? -Yeah.
-区歌就好了 -好
-Sorry. -It's okay.
-抱雪 -没关像
-Sing the song.
-不好意思 -唱歌吧
You're great. That was great.
你唱得很好，棒呆了
Oh, baby, find me
宝只，来找我
Come on. Put your flippers in the air, now.
来啊，把你们的起膀举起来
I'm searching high and low.
我到处寻找，我到处寻找
Yes, there’s somebody out there who needs to find me.
那个人在等著我吧? 那个人，任何人
I'm somebody.
就是我
! wanna love someone Send someone over here
我想找个人来活，我吃了好多车
Somebody to
找个人来…
Mumble!
波波 !
-Who do you think you are? -Yeah, you're spoiling it for everybody.
-你以为你是谁呀? -你壤了大家的惧致
-Take a flying leap. -Yeah, jump in the lake.
-闵殉泳快去啦 -对啊，去跳海啦
Where is my baby?
我的宝贝呢?
Anybody find me, find me Find me, find me
快来找我，来找我…来找我…
Somebody
那个人
Okay, fellas. Cut it out.
好了，大彩儿，别关了
I'm completely terrified.
我真的哇壤了
Gloria?
萝莉亚? 大采儿?
Get up here or I'll come in after you.
上来，不然我下去找你们哦
-Safe! -Oh, yeah!
-安全上电
-You the bomb, bro. -That’s a 9.8.
-你很讲，小兄弟 -我给他9 点8分
-l give you 10. -Why?
-给你满分 -为什么 ?
Oh, no, no, no. Come on. Bring it. Bring it on.
来啊，大埃头，快啊
-Kiss my frozen tushy. -Kiss it. Kiss it.
-有征就来亲我啊 -亲啊
Come here, sausage. Il take you with ketchup.
过来，小肢肠，我要吃了你
But first you got to catch up.
可是你要先提到他才行
Oh, here he comes. You better move in a half an hour.
他追来唾，咱们用慢支作逃命
Let’s get out of here.
快…点…闵…人
-Hey, amigo, do that again. -Do what?
-小兄弟，再做一次 -做什么 ?
-That thing with the-- -The clickety-clickety.
-你刚才跳的… -那个啊
-That. -Yeah, do it.
-就是那个 -对，跳啊
-Come on, come on. -Well, I just kind of go:
-快点快点 -我只是这榜…
-Yeah, yeah, yeah. -Oh, nice.
-棒采了、棒呆了 -讲足
And then this:
然后再这样
Way to go! It’s amazing!
棒呆了，太神了
-Oh, the little whisker. -Look at him.
-可情的小海豹 -看看他
Oh, he's leaving. Oh, no, that was his face!
他要落跑了，你看他一脸衰样
Remember, dumplings, I know where you live.
给我小心点，我知道你们住哪
Yeah, it’s called land, lard face.
我们住在地面上，大肉球
Flop back anytime, rubber butt!
有空来坐坐，大泊呆
See you, fatty.
再见，大胖子
That's cool. "See you, fatty!"
酷奖了，再见，大胖子
Did it take you a while to come up with that one?
你想很久才想出来吗?
All right, way to go, tall guy.
大个子，干得好
Give me fin, give me fin.
遇掌，击党
To the left, to the right i'm getting it, oh, yes
左、右，我会跳了
Look out, here f go
小心点，我学会了
{got it, 1 got it, don't, f had it
我会了，我会了
Oh, my stomach hurts. I gotta pee.
我肚子笑得好痛，我要尿尿
Ain't you coming, tall boy?
你不走，大个儿?
What, you got something better to do?
你有别的事要忙吗?
-No. -Well, then, come along, Fluffy, let’s go.
-没有 -那就来啊，大毛球，走啊
Hey, stretch, you like to party?
高个儿，你喜欢派对吗?
Party? I guess so.
派对 ? 应该喜欢吧
Well, stick with us, baby.
跟著我们就对了
Yeah, because we practically own the action here.
没错，因为我们是派对动物
Mambo!
曼波 !
Everybody's so...spontan-you-us.
大家看起来都好热情哦
Spontan-you-us!
热情如火
And these are the bad times!
这叫做苦中作似
-Yeah, our food chain go loco. -Everyone a bit down.
-是啊，现在食物愈来僵少 -大家都有点肖吕
But it ain’t gonna stop no party!
不过派欠还是要照开
-Viva la party! -Watch me work.
-派对功藏 ! -看看我
Gosh, he’s eating rocks.
天啊，他在吃石头
-You hear what he said? -"Eating rocks."
-有没有贡到? 加 、吃石头^
But he had a rock in his mouth.
他踢里吗著一颗石头
That's no rock, hombre. It’s love stones.
你搞错了，那是爱之石
-For building the nest. -The one with the most pebbles wins.
-用来策梨的 -药集最多就是赢家
You know:
知道吧 女朋友自动送上门
You're not interested in chicas?
你们对女孩子没惧超?9
-Hey, hey, hey. -You kidding?
-哩、哩、哩 ov     ov     ov -天什么玩笑 ?
Without us, the chicas got no boom.
没有我们，她们就没搞
-Why aren't you collecting pebbles? -Pebbles, schmebbles, man.
-你们怎庆不去失石头? -干嘛那庆累呀
We got personality, with a capital Y. Why? Because we're hot.
咱们有个性，热情有劲 因为我们超火辣
Watch and learn, tall boy.
多学著点，大个外
-Hey. Hey, baby. -Over here, mama. Chicky baby.
-嘿，实上贝儿 -这里，淋亮美眉
-Baby. -What are you looking at?
-小辣妹 -你在瞄我吗 ?
-You looking at me? -Come over here.
-来嘛
-Come on, mami. -You see something you like, yes?
-过来，美丑 -和党得我印吗?
I don’t think so. Not tonight, baby.
才怪，你想都别想
Oh, don't be so snooty, booty.
别这样子嘛，小宝贝
That's the way...you like it, you like it
这是你的最党，炼喜欢…
You want it, got it Could've had it, you missed it
你想要，我就给，要不到，算你衰
Look at the feet, huh?
看我们的脚，小姐们
-Where'd you learn that? -The big guy.
-你们从哪里学来的? -大个儿教的
-He from out of town. -He with us.
-他和从外地来的 -咱们是兄弟
-Do it again. -Do it, baby. Show me those flipping feet.
-再来一次 -来啊，让我看看你跳舞
-No, no, no. Sorry, girls. -Some other time maybe.
-不行，抱欢，美眉 -改天再询
You guys are soft in the head, okay?
你们真是呆头钨，我们走吧
-Leave them wanting more, you know? -Hold back till the season.
-这叫欲扒故绕，懂吗? -等她们回来求我们
-You show them what you got. -Either you got it or not.
-任我们气做 -美眉任你挑
-And the Amigos? -We got it!
-咱们这群好麻吉 -迷死你
You think I could get some of it?
我也能那庆迷人吗?
Hombre, you’ve got so much already, you dangerous, baby.
老兄，你已经迷死人了 你是万人迷
You really think so?
你真的这广想?
You kidding? With moves like yours...
少来，你那订会跳
..-you must have all the ladies drooling at your feet.
女孩子看到你哈死了
-l wouldn't say that. -Oh, listen to him. He’s so cute.
-站没有 -区见没有，他超口区
Let me tell something to you.
我告诉你一件事
Except for me, tall boy, you got the most charisma of anybody.
除了我，你的魅力无人能比
Put that ego away, Ramon, you're gonna hurt someone.
别关了，拉蒙，很伤人慎
You so jealous. Just a moment. I hear people wanting something.
你们在嫉嫉我 等一下，好像有人要什么…
Me!
要我 !
One more time now, mambo Mambo, mambo, mambo
再来一次，野波
Mambo!
曼波
Your turn, your turn.
换你啦
Oh, get down.
给他下去
Man, this guy is so accidentally cool.
这像伙真是酷到爆
Okay, okay.
好耶
Mama!
杂呀!
Mommy!
我的妈啊 !
Come on, Fluffy.
来啊，大毛球
Oh, I love gravity.
我超过地心引力
-Oh, I feel like reminiscing. -Remin-icing?
-我好像在自由落体 -自由什么?
-It was too close. -Come on, come on.
-太疯狂了，我不玩了 -来嘛
Hey, guys! Where are we going?
大彩儿，我们要去哪 ?
-We relocating. -Placing ourselves elsewhere.
-去别的地方 -换个环境窟
-But that thing, what was it? -How should we know?
-那是什么玩意? -我们怎知?
-We're penguins. -Very little penguins.
-我们是企鲍 -非常小的企匆
But where did it come from? It’s so weird, so alien.
他打哪来的? 长得好怪，像外星怪客
-What'’s he talking about? -Some hombre called Elian.
-他在说什么? -不知道，什么怪肢
I don’t know a guy Elian. I knew a guy named Estevan--
我不认识怪脚，我认识肉脚…
-Not Estevan, Elian. -Guys, we have a mystery here.
-不是肉肝，他说怪有 -这是个诬，天大的恋转
So? What are we supposed to do about it?
又怎样 ? 我们该怎么办呢 ?
Amigos, we gotta get to the bottom of this thing.
我们一定要查个水落石出
Big guy, let me tell something to you. Come close. Don't be afraid.
大个儿，我告诉你一件事 近一点，别怕
-That’s all you need?
-你要答案? -对
-Nothing else? -No.
-只要答案? -没别的?
Then this is very easy.
那很简单
-Lovelace. -Go see Lovelace.
-去找党拉斯
-Genius, Ramon. You are the man. -Thank you.
-拉蒙，你真天才 -谢谢
-l take a moment for myself. -Let’s go.
-走啦
-Bow down. -You the man.
-崇拜我吧 -你最棒
-That’s enough, I feel your love. -Who’s Lovelace?
-角了，多谢了 -谁是爱拉斯9
-Lovelace is the guru. -Go see Lovelace.
-他是个通赶大师 -去找党拉斯
-He got the answer to everything. -Everything.
-他是万事通 -什么都懂
-Really? -Ask him, he never wrong.
-真的吗? -去问他，他不会错
But first, you gonna need a pebble.
首先，你需要找一颗石头
Hold it, y'all. 1 have a warning for the audience.
暂停一下，我要警告贡办朋友
Ladies, please, avert your eyes...
小姐们，请你们别过头去
...-because I've been known to hypnotize.
不然会被我催眠
You heard the voice, now you're about to meet...
大家凰到声音，现在要见到…
...the one and only Lovelace, in the flesh...
独一乱二的过拉斯的本尊
tight here, right on, right now.
此不、此时、此刻
The devotion, please.
交出你的贡品
Oh, yeah.
好
And now, your question.
很好，说出你的问题
...my wife has disappeared. Is she alive?
爱拉斯大师，我老效不见了 她还活著吗?
is she alive now? Separate the truth from the jive
她还活著吗 ? 我来帮你解惑
Speak to me, oh, mystic beings
告诉我，奥秘之神
Yes! She's happy and you're in her thoughts.
她很快乐，你在她的心中
Is she with another male?
她跟别人跑了吗?
One pebble, one question. Next!
一颗石头一个问题，下一个
Oh, Serene One. Please ask the mystic beings...
大师，请问奥秘之神
..-Will 1 ever be as rich as you?
我会不会和你一样有钱?
In your dreams, Jean. Next!
别作荔了，下一个 !
-Go ahead. Go ahead. -Get up there, big guy.
-快点，去啊，去啊 -快去啊，大个子
-That’s it. Don’t be scared. -Gentleman, please! One at a time.
-就是这样啤，别怕 -各位，拜证，一次一个
-We with him. -Yeah, we together.
-我们是一起的 -对，我们在一起
-He got a beautiful question. Go. -Do it.
-他有个很棒的问题 -快问啊
Just don't look him in the eye.
不要看他的眼睛
Have you ever been abducted by aliens?
你被外星怪客绑架过吗?
Excuse me? What kind of question is that? Next!
这算哪门子问题? 下一个
No, wait, sefior.
等等，大师
I met a skua once, with something like that on his foot, said he was abducted by aliens.
有一焦贼鸥，脚上也有那玩意 他说他被外星怪客绑架
This, friend, is my sacred talisman...
这是我的神桂访身符
Talisman, talisman
护身符，访身符
... bestowed on me by the mystic beings...
奥秘之神赐给我的礼物
Mystic beings
奥秘之神
...during my epic journey of enlightenment...
保佑我在悟道神于之旅
...to the forbidden shore.
抵达禁忌彼岸
Forbidden shore
禁忌彼岸
Oh, say it one more.
再唱一次
-Forbidden shore -Oh, yeah
-禁忌彼岸 -好耶
Wait, you saw mystic beings?
你见过奥秘之神?
I hear them! They speak through me!
那是天夭，我传尼天总
There’s a power that makes me stand upon this tower!
神力，让我撞有扰跟法力
Did they have front-ways eyes? Did they probe you? Strap you down?
他们眼睛挤在一起吗? 有没有戳你? 把你五花大绑?
Enough! "Did they probe me?”
区了，有没有戳我…关你屁事呀
Too many questions! You don’t have enough pebbles, fool.
你问题太多了“，丙品不锡
You haven't answered any of my questions.
你没有回答我的问题
-How many questions he got? -We've all got stuff to ask!
-他有多少问题? -我们都有问题要问
Enough!
不要吵了!
You bring this stranger before me.
你们带来这焦陌生企秽
He doubts my powers. He compares me to a skua.
他质疑我的法力 居然拿我跟虐鸥比
The voices are shrieking in my head.
天神的声音快要消失了
They say, "Lovelace, who is this fool?
他们说 : “爱拉斯，这傻朴是谁?7
Tell him! Tell him to go forth and multiply!"
告诉他去…好好繁衍后代
Come to think of it...
提到这一点
...why don't we all go forth and multiply?
咱们何不都去繁衍和后代?
-Lovelace. -What he saying?
-噢，党拉斯 -他是什么意思?
-It’s mating season. -Already?
-交配季到了 -到了吗?
I will retire now to my couch of perpetual indulgence.
我要休息了，好好享受一下
-Okay, ladies, who's first? -Me!
-好了，谁要先来? -我
One at a time. Don’t touch the talisman, baby, please.
一次一个，不准摸议身符
Hey, wait a minute. Wait a minute. What about us?
等一下，我们怎广闪?
Lovelace, Lovelace, Lovelace!
爱拉斯…爱拉斯…
Hear me!
匠好了
There's not enough love in the world.
世上的爱永遗都不锡
Turn to the penguin next to you.
面对身净的企穆
Put your flippers up. Fluff him up a little bit.
附起你的翅膀，好好摸他一下
And give him a great big hug.
再给他一个大大的拉抱
Okay, ladies.
好了，小姐们
Oh, make that little noise again, girl.
再来亲亲抱抱
Hey, what he got we don’t got, man?
他有的我们也有
-What you hugging me for? -He told me to.
-你干嘛抱我? -是他叫我抱的
-Get away. -No, you like it.
-走开 -你明明就喜允
Get off him, Ramon.
放并他，拉蒙
Stretch, got any stones where you come from?
大个多 ，你有带家乡的石头吗?
-We don't collect stones. -You don't? Why not?
-我们不失石头 -真的? 为什么?
We live on the ice.
我们住在冰原上
So how you win the heart of the ladies?
你们怎订赢得女人心?
Well, we sing.
我们唱歌
-Stop! That's crazy! -You're kidding, right?
-少来，太扯了 -你在天玩笑?
No. We sing to each other.
真的，我们对唱情歌
If someone special likes your song, you know....
如果有人欣赏你的情歌
Oh, and you have someone special?
有人欣赏你吗?
-A tall beauty in your dark romantic past? -Of which you never speak?
-你有没有大个儿女朋友? -说来区聘嘛
Well, sort of.
算是有吧
Hey, let's go check it out. Maybe she got some friends.
带我们去，也许她有姐妹淘
I like them tall.
我喜欢高个子女生
It's never gonna work.
我跟她不可能有结果
-Hey, big guy. -It’s the loving season.
-大个儿 -这是伙爱季节耶
All you gotta do is sing.
唱首歌就好了
That's the problem. I can’t.
这就是问题，我不会唱歌
-You a bird, ain't you? -All birds can sing.
-你是企鸣吧? -企镶都会唱歌
! don't sing like the birdie do
我们企鹅都会喝…
All right.
好吧
Find me, find me
找个人来…
What's he doing?
他在干嘛?
-l think he’s singing. -I know singing, that’s not singing.
-好像在唱歌 -我匠过歌，那不是唱歌
l heard an animal once do that, but then they rolled him over, he was dead.
我区过有勤物像这样惨叫 他叫完就措掉了
Yeah. And when she sings, it darn near breaks your heart.
可是她唱歌会让你如流如酵
You in tragic shape, man.
你真是太惨了
-Don't worry. We can fix it. -We can?
-安啤，我们会帮你搞定 -真的吗?
-Absolutely. We can. We can.
-那还用说 -行吗?
-Really? -Yes! Let me tell something to you.
-真的吗? -真的，让我告诉你
-Come close. Closer. You wanna sing? -Yeah.
-近一点，再近一点，你想唱歌? -对
-You sure? -Absolutely.
-你确定? -非常确定
You making fun of me? Then this is very easy.
你在要我吗了 这样就好办了
Really? Gosh, if 1 could sing, that would change everything.
真的吗? 要是我会唱歌就太好了
You will sing. You just got to do exactly what I say.
你会唱歌，只要照我的话去做
-Okay. -Did I say "okay"?
-好 -我有说好邑 ?
-No. -No. What did I say?
-没有 -对，我说什么?
-Do exactly what you say. -Exactly what I say.
-照你的话去做 -照我的话去做
Don't push me ‘Cause I'm close to the edge
不要吉我，因为我就快要崩溃
I'm trying not to lose my...
我不想要失去我的理智
Gloria
萝莉亚
It's like a jungle sometimes it makes me wonder
入佛在羔林中，真想就此放球
Midnight creeps so slowly
黑夜缓名进带
Into hearts of those Who need more than they get
遥向需求无度、永不满足的人
Daylight deals a bad hand
白韦的赌局
To a penguin who has laid too many bets
下注太高的企瘤一手烟牌
it make love to you Like you want me to
我和你温存，任你气布
And I'll hold you tight, baby, all...
我会抱紧你，实内，我…
Gloria
萝莉亚
The mirror stares you in the face
镜子瞪著你，当著你的面
And says, "Baby--"
说著，实中
ft don't work
不搭调
You say your prayers Though you don't care
你识心祈祷分不在乎
Boys! Boys!
各位，各位…
Boys!
各位!
Mumble?
波波?
Mumble.
波波 !
Oh, hi, Gloria.
，葛痢亚，人好
And this is you?
这是你唱的?
Well, ! would, if it were really you, yeah.
当然，如果真的是你唱的
Well, it is me, sort of.
算是我唱的吧
Yeah.
是哦
Turn around.
转过去
-Turn around. -Why?
-转过去 -为什么 ?
-Well, why not? -Well....
-为什么不? -因为…
-What do you know? -Yeah.
-我就知道 -是啊
-Gloria. -Mumble, how could you?
-葛莉亚 -你怎麻能这样 ?
Hello.
你好
I know size can be daunting, but don't be afraid. I love you.
我知道我很矮小 不过别怕，我党
-Gloria, please. -l love you.
-葛莉亚，拜斌 -我爱你
-Gloria!
-葛莉亚
-Please, Gloria, wait! -Please, Gloria, wait for me!
-葛莉亚，求求你等等 -求求你，等等我
-Stop it! -Okay.
-我一看到你就凌未条 -别关了
Mumble, what could you possibly be thinking?
你在想什么 ?
I don’t know what else to do.
我不知道该怎入做
Oh, Gloria, no.
萝莉亚，别这样
Go up there, right now.
快去追啊…
Daylight deals a bad hand...
白攻的赌局…
Gloria. Gloria.
萝莉亚、葛莉亚
Sing to this.
跟著我的节拍唱
Mumble, you're embarrassing me.
波波，你害我党得好糠
Baby...it don’t work.
波波，这不搭调
Baby
宝中
So slowly
逼向…
So slowly into hearts of those
遥向需求无度，永不满足的人
Daylight deals a bad hand
白韦的赌局
To a penguin that has laid too many bets
下注太高的企瘤一手烟牌
The mirror stares you in the face
镜子瞪著你，当著你的面
And says, "Baby...it don't work”
说著，裤只，不搭调
You say your prayers Though you don't care
你识心祈祷分不在乎
You sing and you shake the hurt
你唱歌，件不金真心
Dance!
跌吧 上
Boogie wonderland
不霸乐园
Dance
跳吧,
Midnight creeps so slowly
黑夜缓名进带
Into hearts of men Who need more than they get
遥向需求无度，永不满足的人
Daylight deals a bad hand
白韦的赌局
To a penguin who has laid too many bets
下注太高的企瘤一手烟牌
The mirror stares you in the face
镜子瞪著你，当著你的面
And says, "Baby...it don't work”
说著，裤只，不搭调
You say your prayers Though you don't care
你识心祈祷分不在乎
You dance and shake the hurt
你跳舞，和分不金真心
Dance!
跌吧 上
Mumble!
曼波 !
Boogie wonderland
不霸乐园
Dance, dance, dance
跳，跳， 路，受波 !
My brothers
兄弟们
You look so beautiful to me, baby
在我眼中最美的是你
-Mumble. -Hey, Miss Viola.
-曼波 ! -薇拉老师
-All the love in the world can't be gone -Mumble!
-世界的过不会消失 -曼波 !
-All the need to be loved can't be wrong
-需要党不会错
Disgraceful!
太委脸了
Who do they think they are?
他们算什么东西
Where is Noah? This is getting out of hand.
诺哈呢? 情况完全失控
Go!
跳吧,
Hey, Memphis. It’s your boy, Mumble.
曼菲斯，是你儿子，波波
-Mumble?
-波波? -波波
No, no. No, it’s "Mambo." O!
不，是波
Baby. They're saying, "Mumble.”
宝上中，他们说…受波 !
Boogie!
不霸 !
Behold, Noah, look!
看啊，谐哈，你看
This was an omen from the start and now we have this uprising.
这和从一开始就是壤预兆 现在大家都造反了
Stop! Stop!
停!停!
Stop this unruly nonsense!
不要再胡关下去了
Stop it right now!
不要再跳了
A little self-control, if you please!
拜旗你们控制一下自己
You bring this disorder, this aberration, to the very heart of our community.
你们在拒造又动 让我们的社会充满不安
Have you lost your minds?
你们都站了吗?
-We're just having fun. -Harmless fun.
-我们只是在玩啊 -又没有伤害
"Harmless"? It is this kind of backsliding that has brought the scarcity upon us.
-没有伤害? -这征行为带来了可怕的急芒
Excuse me, smiley. Can you speak plain penguin, please?
歹势，请你说白话
He thinks the food shortage has something to do with me.
他认为食物短缺是我的错
Do you not understand that we can only survive here when we're in harmony?
我们只有和和谐共处才能生存下去
When you and your foreign friends lead us into your easy ways...
当你和你的外地朋友在这里胡并
...you offend the Great 'Guin.
就冒犯了企镶歌神
You invite him to withhold his bounty.
融袖收回送我们的思跑
-He rules the seasons. -He giveth and he can taketh away.
-礼掌管著季节 -被能给予，就能收回
Wait a minute. Happy feet can’t cause a famine.
慢著，快乐脚不会造成饥荒
If thy kind of pagan display did not cause it, then what did?
不是你们造成的，会是什么 ?
I think it comes from outside. Way beyond the ice.
有外力因素，在冰原之外
There are things out there, things we don’t understand.
那里有一种我们不了解的生物
-Mysteries. -Mind-boggling mysteries.
-那是个证 -天大的谜转
-Mystic beings. -Yeah, aliens.
-神秘生物 -对，外星怪客
-He’s mad. -No, aliens.
-他瘦了 -不，是外星怪客
-l hear they're smart. -He’s insane.
-蓝说他们很隐明 -他瘦了
No, they might be smarter than all of us. Who knows?
他们可能比我们都隐明
He drove the fish away, now he’s ranting this rubbish!
他把急超走，现在又在鬼扯羔
-Hey, let me tell something to you. -Don't touch me, you filthy vermin.
-我告诉你一件事 -不要碰我，短腿企咏
-Hey, watch it. -And so it follows.
一小心 上 -这是恶性循环
-You, Mumble Happy Feet, must go. -Hear, hear.
-快乐脚波波一定要离开 -对、对
Don't you take one step, sweetheart.
一步都不准走，儿子
You have as much right to be here as any of these daffy old fools.
你和那些老古板一样有权留下来
Norma Jean, I'll deal with this.
诺斑珍，让我来不理
Pa?
和爸?
Mumble, you must renounce your so-called friends...
波波，你要唾素你所谓的朋友
...your peculiar thoughts, your strange ways.
奇怪的想法，施翼的行为
-Memphis. -If we are devout...
-曼菲斯 ! -如果你虞诚…
...Ssincere In Our praise, the fish will return.
虔诚祈祷就能解决急荒
-But, Pa-- -Listen, boy, 1 was a backslider myself.
-可是，和爸… -风好，我也曾刀反传统
l was careless and now we're paying the price.
我太粗心，现在报应来了
What's this got to do with Mumble?
这和波波有什么关像?
-It's why he is the way he is. -There’s nothing wrong with him!
-我害他爸成这样 -他没有问题
-Face it, our son's all messed up. -He’s not messed up, hear me?
-承认吧“，咱们的儿子有问题 -他没问题，匠见吗了?
-Believe me, I know. -How can you say that?
-相信我，我很清楚 -你怎广能这订说?
Because when he was just an egg, I dropped him!
他还是蛋的时候，我把他弄掉
Memphis.
曼菲斯 !
Mumble.
波波
Oh, my poor little Mumble.
我可情的小波波
But, Mom, I’m perfectly fine.
可是我很正常
-No. No, you're not, boy. -That’s right.
-不，你不正常 -就是说嘛
For all our sakes, you must stop this freakiness with the feet.
为了大家好，别再乱跳舞了
Your father speaks wisely. Heed his suffering heart and repent.
你父亲非常明智 他痛苦的心志就靠你来手平
But it just doesn’t make any sense.
这一点都没有道理
Then your arrogance leaves us no choice!
你例慢的态度融我们别扰选择
No, wait.
不，等等
Please, son, you can do this. It ain’t so hard.
孩子，你做得到，这疮不难
Don’t ask me to change, Pa, because I can’t.
别有还我改演，我做不到
And that, my brethren, is the end of it.
同胞们，那就这样吧
You, begone!
你，滚吧
-Mumble. -No, Ma, it’s okay. It's okay.
-波波 -不，妈，不要紧
When I find out what’s happening to the fish...
等我查明鱼芒的原因…
[Il be back.
就会回来
Let me through? Let me through.
让我过去，借过一下
-Mumble, you don’t have to go. -Let it be.
-波波，你不必走 -让他走吧
-Gloria. -No. No, Dad, this isn’t fair.
-葛莉亚 -不，这太不公平了
Gloria, listen to your father.
萝莉亚，隐人爸的话
My folks were always putting him down
我的爸杂老是看不起他
Down, down, down
看不起他…
They said he came From the wrong side of town
他们说他自来下流社会
He came from the wrong side of town
说他来自下流社会
They told me he was bad
他们说他很壤
So bad
很壤
-But 1 know he was sad -So sad
-但是我懂他的翡 -他的翡
Vit never forget him The leader of the pack
我永带忘不了那个带头老大
We sing the heart of our true friend, Mumble.
我们唱出波波的心静
You are a nation of peeny-weeny, piffling, piccolini, piddly-diddly pouft!
你们是小心眼小鼻子小眼栈 小家子所的小气鬼
Together, we prevail.
团结力量大
In the wisdoms, we trust.
在歌声中互信
We trust.
互信
Look out
小心…
Don’t worry, tall guy. My father also called me a pitiful loser.
安啦，大个儿 我爸也说我是没用的肉脚
Look how I turn out.
我还不是好好的
You're not helping, Ramon.
你在帮倒忙，拉和蒙
He gonna be okay. All he gotta do is find out what happened to the fish.
他不会有事的 只要查清楚急都去哪了
-How he gonna do that? -He think of something.
-他要怎麻查? -他会有办法的
-The aliens. -What?
-外星怪容 -什么?
-I’m gonna talk to the aliens. -How you gonna find aliens?
-我要去找外星怪客 -你要怎庆找到外星怪客?
-Lovelace. -He don't like you. He don’t like you at all.
-过拉斯 -可是他根本就不喜获你
That's okay. I'll appeal to his better nature.
没关你，我会激起他的同情心
-How you gonna do that? -Cruel and unusual punishment?
-你要怎麻做? -对他最刑钳打?
-Unimaginable torture? -Imaginable torture?
-准以想像的酷刑 ? -可以想像的酷刑 ?
-Your singing? -No!
-你的歌声 ? -不要吧
"Can anybody find me"...
有谁可以为我…
-You're cracking the ice! -Avalanche!
-冰都被你震裂了 -大冰骨
Yes, okay. Thank you.
多谢了
Lovelace. You there?
党拉斯，你在吗?
Lovelace!
爱拉斯?
Lovelace.
爱拉斯 !
Is this a bad time?
时机好像不太对哩
I know we don’t have an appointment, but--
我知道我们没预约…
Just one question and I want a straight answer.
只有一个问题，我要你老实回答
Where do I find the mystic beings?
到哪里可以找到奥秘之神?
Why don't he speak?
他怎麻不说话?
Lovelace, you okay?
党拉斯，你没事吧?
-Boy, he’s possessed. -It’s a seizure! It’s a seizure!
-他中政了 -癌痫症发作
-Open the beak. -Grab his tongue.
-把嘴儿开 -拉出舌头
He’s choking. That thing around his neck, it’s too tight.
他脖子上的东西勒太紧了
-Well, why didn’t you say so? -On three.
-你怎庆不早说? -数到三
Stop! Listen! No! Amigos! Amigos! Stop!
-一、二、三、四! -住手，大彩儿，住手 !
-What? -You're hurting him.
-干嘛? -你们伤到他了
Any better?
有没有好一点
Lovelace, how did you get that thing around your neck?
你脖子上的东西是怎么来的?
-It was bestowed on him. -By the mystic beings.
-神赐给他的 -奥秘之神
-They didn't bestow it? -No.
-不是吗? -不是
Oh, come on, he don't know what he’s saying.
拜旗，他脑袋糊渗了
You were swimming and it just got caught around your neck.
你在游泳，结果被那玩意套住
Oh, no way. He the guru.
不可能，他是大师
Lovelace, did you ever actually meet a mystic being?
爱拉斯，你见过奥秘之神吗 ?
Officially?
真的吗?
No.
没有
I knew it! It’s all a lie.
我就知道，他在骗人
But this belongs to someone.
这一定属於某个人
If we could find them, I bet you they could take it off.
找到他，就一定能弄掉
Show me where you found it. I'm sure they could help us. You and me both.
带我去，他们一定能帮忙 我们一起去
Two words, three syllables.
四个字，我猜猜看
-What is it? -You're dying?
-什么? -你快指了?
No, no, wait. Past, past, your past life.
不对，通去，你的过去…
You're passing gas.
你在放屁
Now he thinks he’s an elephant seal.
不对，他说他是海象
No, no, no. Go over the mountains.
不对，翻越那座山
-Go over the mountains! -Through the land of the elephant seals.
-翻越那座山 -前往海象王国
-Beyond the land of the elephant seals. -Beyond the land of the elephant seals!
-越过海象王国 -答对了 !
-Wait. -What?
-等等 -什么?
l hear voices.
我匠到瑶言
-There is a voice. -Where?
-传来一个声音 -哪里了
-There’s a little voice on the wind. -Mumble!
-风中传来微弱的叫瑶 -波波 !
-Listen. -Mumble Happy Feet.
-注意风 -波波快乐脚
-Gloria? -Gloria!
-葛莉亚? -葛莉亚!
Hey, you got a stalker. She's obsessed with you, man.
有人跟距你，她很哈你哦
Il can’t believe it's you.
我不敢相信是你
What are you doing here?
你跑来做什么 ?
All the love in the world can't be gone
世界的过不会消失
All the need to be loved can't be wrong
需要过的人绝对不会错
-Oh, my. -So which way, twinkletoes?
-哦，天哪 -往哪走，舞王?
No, no, no. If you come, you may never get back home.
不行，炼跟我走就回不了家
Fine by me.
我无所谓
Gloria, you have a life back there. I don’t. 1 mean, we don’t. Not out here.
你过得好好的，我不一样 我们不能在这壬过日子
How can we keep an egg safe? That's if we ever had an egg.
怎麻保访蛋? 如果要生蛋的话
Well, [ don’t need an egg to be happy.
我不必生蛋就很快乐
You say that now, but what about later when all your friends have eggs?
等你朋友都生了就会后悔
Then I'll have you.
我有你就好
Now he’s going to pledge his soul forever.
立下山盟海将的机会来了
-Gloria. -Here it comes.
-葛莉亚 -他要说了
I'm a particular kind of guy, the kind of guy who needs his own space.
我是个怪胎 我需要自己的空间
It’s not you, it’s me.
你没问题，是我的错
I'm just not up for a serious relationship right now.
我玩没准备认真谈感情
What he’s trying to do now is he’s pushing her away. Let's watch.
他想要起她回家 好戏上场吗
No matter what you say or do, you're stuck with me.
不管你怎订说我都跟定你了
Oh, come on. As if you're not totally thrilled that I'm here.
少装了，你看到我很高导
-Now she got him on the ropes. -See, right there is your problem.
-她把他逼到死角 -瞧，这就是你的问题
You think you're irresistible, don’t you?
你自以为是菌人迷
I don't care where you're from, that’s got to hurt.
这种话真伤人
-Excuse me? -Gloria’s so gorgeous, Gloria’s so talented.
-你说什么? -葛莉亚美若天仙，才昔洋溢
What?
什么?
Just because you can hit a few high notes.
会壬高音有什么了不起
You got a problem with my singing?
你对我的歌瑶有意见?
No, it’s perfectly fine.
我党得还好?
-"Fine"? -If you like that sort of thing.
-还好? -如果炼喜欢这味的
-It’s a little Nana Tootsie for my taste. -What?
-我觉得你的曲风太沁狗血了 -什么?
You know, showy, flashy, froufrou.
没品味，太炉情，太区乐了
-"Froufrou”? -That’s right.
-太苑乐了 -没错
Coming from someone who thinks it’s cool to jig up and down really fast on the spot...
你只会用两售脚乱跳天持
...like some twitchy idiot.
像个抽筋的小隆
You stubborn, hippity-hoppity fool!
固执又可显的讨灰鬼
Right back at you.
轴得好
Amigo, that was a good thing you do.
你这广做是为她好
She is going to be so much better off without you.
她离开你会过更好的生活
She is going to find a good, steady guy to comfort her...
她会找到安份的企秽来安祭她
..and love her up real good and raise a big family.
真心爱她，组织大家庭
-Ramon. -And then she’s going to let herself go--
-拉蒙 -然后她会变成黄脸朔…
Ramon. He’s hurting. He’s hurting bad.
他很心痛，痛到不行
Oh, listen, listen, don't hold it in or you explode. You got to let it out.
隐好，别强忍，不然会爆炸
You just let it out. You let it out.
你要发小出来 发小出来吧
Everybody, turn away for a moment.
大彩儿，转过去
If she leave him now
她郊开他，带走他的一部分
Don't, baby, please, don't go
宝内，请不要走
Please, guys.
拜旗你们…
No more singing.
不要再喝了
Then she say to me, "Enough, you are making me nauseous.”
她跟我说 : “你让我好想吐7
So I become silent, almost moody, and you know what she says?
我就生况所不说话 你知道她怎麻说?
“You never share. You got to let it out.”
“你从来不说，你要发流出来
-Ramon, come on. -Let it out. Let it out.
-拉蒙，金了 -发漫出来
Stop it! Let it go.
钓了啦
-I never had a good relationship in my life. -Give him a hug. Give him a hug.
-我这草子不曾有过美好伙情 -抱抱他
-l let it out! -There we go.
-我发流出来了 -开始了
-[ let it out. -l know. Get over it.
-我知道，别再发小了
-Can you keep going? -Yeah.
-你还能走吗 ? -可以啊
-What’s that smell? -It wasn't me.
-什么味道 ? -不是我
Hey, Fluffy, we're following you. Get up here.
大毛球，是你在带路，快上来
So these elephant seals, they're not penguin eaters, are they?
这些海象 他们不会吃企唔，对吧?
I don’t know. I believe they are herbivores.
不知道，他们是草食动物
-What? -You know, kelp-suckers.
-什么? -就是吃草的啦
Here we go, Lovelace. Come on.
来吧，党拉斯
Jump in time. Jump in time.
该跳唆，该跳噬
-Okay, let’s do it. -Okay, okay, okay. Ready?
-好了，我们走吧 -好、好、好了吗?
I can do this. I can do this. I got to trick myself.
我可以的…我要驴自己做得到
Boy, look at that. What?
你看，那是什么 ?
You blokes better be lost, because trespassing’s a crime.
你们最好快滚，擅阁民宅是犯罪
-We're just passing through. -Yeah. We're with him.
-我们只是路过 -是他带我们来的
You wouldn't be heading over them distant hills...
你们该不会想越过高山
..and through the blizzard country?
穿越过冰天雪地吧?
If it’s the only way to the forbidden shore, yeah.
这样才能抵达禁忌彼岸
Crikey.
了不起
You might come face to face with an annihilator.
你们可能会面对面碰上终极杀手
An alien annihilator?
外星怪客，终极角手?
Too right. Cut you up as soon as look at you.
没错，一见到你就会宁了你
Waste every living thing in their path.
见一个杀一个
Could they be annihilating the fish?
急也是他们角的吧?
Every living thing.
只要是活的都逃不了
Merciless, mate. Merciless.
冷血无情，毫不留情
Even if you're a whopping great whale...
就算你是巨大鲸急
...they drag your sorry carcass ashore...
他们照样把你拖到岸上
...dice you up, melt you down, and turn you into fun food.
旭你的皮，割你的肉 把你变成美味大餐
One day you're a big old whale...
你本来是条大鲸急，一转限…
..-fun food.
…就是美味大餐
Someone's gotta stop them.
一定要有人阻止他们
Oh, yeah? What's gonna be your approach?
是吗?你要怎太做?
If I could just talk to them.
我可以找他们谈
Appeal to their better nature.
激起他们的同情心
When that crafty little trick pays off, you be sure to let us know, won't you?
成功了记得要通知我们哦
All right, Lovelace, let's go.
爱拉斯，我们走吧
See you, Lovelace.
再见，营拉斯
Your funeral, mate.
你死定了
Oh, man!
天啊
-Push tight. -Okay.
-加油 -好
Come on, guys. Let’s do it.
我们可以的，用力
You can do it. Come on, push!
你可以的，加油 !
What's that noise?
那是什么声音 ?
There's no noise.
没有瑶音
-No gasping. No wheezing. -Where's Lovelace?
-没咖吟，没喘气 -党拉斯呢?
Sometimes a brave penguin will just slip away to die.
有了时候勇敢的企奖会躲起来等死
Do you think he went to a happy place?
他上了天堂吗?
-Probably. -No, no. I think he went this way.
-有可能 -不，他往这超走了
Come on. Let’s go.
来吧，我们走
Lovelace!
爱拉斯 !
Hello?
你好
Is there anyone there?
有人在吗?
-No-- No need to shout. -Somebody might hear you.
-别叫这广大声 -会被人听见
His feet don't look too good.
他的脚好像有点跋
-He rested here. -Now he's on his belly!
-他在这里休息 -现在是用爬的
-No, this way. -You don’t want to know what he did here.
-他往这下去了 -你不会想知道他在干嘛
-You're right. -There he is. Lovelace!
-你说得对 -他在那里
-All right! Lovelace! -Lovelace!
-太好了，壳拉斯… -党拉斯 !
-Oh, look at Lovelace. -We're here.
-看看爱拉斯 -我们来了
-Are you okay? -Come on, man. Hang in there, buddy.
-你没事吧? -加油，撞下去，老哥
What is it?
那是什么?
Oh, look. There’s one for everyone.
瞧，大家都有份
Hang in there, Lovelace. I know they're here somewhere.
挤下去，他们就在附近
-Why would they leave all this behind? -I don’t know.
-他们干嘛丢下这些 ? -不知道
Hey.
哩 ov
-Tell them we come in peace. -We come in peace!
-快说我们属好和平 -我们过好和平
-Lovelace.
-过拉斯
-Oh, buddy, come on.
-老兄.…
-Are you okay? -Hang in there, buddy.
-你没事吧? -老兄，接下去
-Oh, that’s not good. -Stay calm.
-大事不妙 -冷静点
-That’s not good.
-不好了
-Okay, don't stay calm! -Panic!
-糙了，冷静不了了 -抓狂了
Oh, no, no!
糟了
-Oh, they’re making us appe-teasers. -They’re appe-teasing us!
-他们把我们当点心 -他们在要我们
We're all gonna die.
我们死定了
Whatever you do, stay out of the water!
扰论如何千菌不要下水
-Stay out of the water. -Don't go in the water!
-别下水 -不要下水
Lovelace, don’t go in the water!
党拉斯，不要下水
Lovelace, hang in there!
爱拉斯，挤住…
Hang in there!
撑住
Get your dirty tongue off him!
不准你支他一根汗毛
No, no, no!
惨了
Stay out of the water!
元水下点
-Mumble!
-波波
Lovelace!
爱拉斯 !
Rejoice!
解腕了
-Help! -Reach out!
-救命啊! -伸出手来
Thank you, my brother, thank you!
谢谢，小兄弟
l wasn’t scared! 1 wasn’t scared!
老子不怕
Oh, my beautiful brother, thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you!
小兄弟，你太神了，谢谢你…
-Go, Lovelace! You the man! -Go, go, go, go, go!
-加油，党拉斯，了不起 -加油，加油
Enough!
金了
It's a bad day for you!
今天算你们雨个倒祷
You dealing with Lovelace now!
遇见我党拉斯
-And my man, Mumble, here. -You tell them, Lovelace.
-和我兄弟波波 -说得好，爱拉斯
Begone, demon fish. Adios.
滚吧，昧魔急
That's right.
没错
You hightail it back to your mamas.
快滚蛋，立刻滚回去找你老妈
-How did he do that? -Don’t make me come in the water.
-他是怎么做到的? -不要融我下水
I'll come after your sons and daughters.
我会让你绝子绝防
I’m gonna give you the bad eye.
我要诅咒你永世不得超生
A whole bunch of them.
一大堆的怪物
They gonna rule the world.
他们要统治世界
It’s gotta be them.
一定就是他们
-If it is, 1 don’t wanna know about it. -They don’t even know we exist.
-不管是什么我都不想知道 -他们根本不知道我们的存在
Let me tell something to you.
我告诉你
This is the end of the road. It’s over.
你已经走到意头了
You did everything penguinly possible.
你旭了最大的努力
-You found the aliens. -We gonna testify to that.
-找到了外星怪客 -我们会作证
We'll tell your whole laughing-boy nation they were dead wrong about you.
跟那群老古板说他们看错你了
Now, let’s all go back home. Right now.
我们回家吧，走吧
Right on.
没错
-Could I ask a favor of you? -Sure.
-请你们攻个忙 -好啊
-What kind of favor? -Could you make sure Gloria’s okay?
-帮什么忙? -帮我照刁葛莉亚
-And my ma. -What?
-还有我怒 -什么?
And if you see Pa...
要是看到我爸
..-tell him I tried.
跟他说…我虽力了
Okay, what you talking about?
你在说什么?
I'm gonna stop them taking our fish.
我要阻止他们抓走我们的刍
How you gonna do that, Mumble?
你要怎庆阻止他们?
Adios, amigos!
再见，兄弟们
Amigo! He did it.
老天 ! 他是玩真的
You believe that?
哇塞，你相信吗?
How we gonna tell his mama he bring us all this way just to kill himself?
我们要怎床跟他杂交代? 他带我们大老速跑来，然后自杀
No. He didn’t. Look.
他没有自贡，你们看
He loco maniac.
他真瘦狂
First ever flying flipper bird.
他是第一焦会习的企先
How tall you think that tall boy was?
你们说化勇不勇敢?
Who could say? Taller than anyone.
他比任何企身都勇敢
Hey, it's me, Lovelace...
是我，爱拉斯
...formerly known as "guru."
曾经是知名精神大师
I'm gonna be telling your story, Happy Feet...
我要说出你的故事，快乐脚
...long after you dead and gone!
纪念你的英勇事距
Hey! Hey!
哩、哩) ov   oo
Enraged by their indifference...
怪物的冷漠激怒了波波
..-he followed them long after they were gone from his sight.
即使走下了，波波还是紧追不失
He ventured further than any of us had gone before...
到了我们想像不到的地方
..--beyond all hope of return.
回家的路途这下无期
Swept up by the great currents...
他被强大的海流溃著
...he was carried endlessly across vast oceans...
在茫范大海中一直淋流
...to worlds unknown.
来到一个未知的世界
Excuse me. What is this place?
请问这是什么地方?
You're in heaven, Dave. Penguin heaven.
这壬是天堂，企编天堂
Is it anywhere near Emperor Land?
在帝王企物的王国附近吗?
It's wherever you want it to be.
你希望是什么就是什么
Try the water, Dave. It’s really real.
下水试试吧，很像真的海水
{ heard tell, when he finally saw aliens up close...
我观说他终葵看到外星怪客
...they were just as the skua had described.
他们的长相和虐欧形容的一样
Excuse me. Why are you taking our fish?
你们为什么抢走我们的急?
Big, ugly penguins without feathers on their fat, flabby faces.
就像超醒的企镶 只是胖脸上面没有玖毛
Why are you taking our fish? You're kind of killing us out there.
你们为什么抢走我们的急? 那麻做会害死我们
No! No, wait!
等等，别走
Oh, my.
天啊
Hello. Hello from Emperor Land. Good afternoon.
我来自沉王企奖王国，午安
Why are you taking our fish?
你们为什么要抢走我们的急?
I'm sure you don't mean to, but you're causing an awful lot of grief.
也疾你们不是故意的 可是你们那样会害惨我们
Am I not making myself clear? I'm speaking plain penguin.
我说的话你们区懂吗? 我说的是企篇话
Penguin! Don’t you understand? You're stealing our fish.
你们匠不懂吗? 你们偷走我们的急
Oh, please, anyone, talk to me!
拜斌，请你们回答我
For pity’s sake, you're stealing our F-I-S--
老天和敬，你们偷走我们的急…
After three days, he would lose his voice.
三天和后他的嗓子完全沙吧
After three months...
三个月禾…
.--he would all but lose his mind.
他几乎快要发况
So you found the fish, baby.
你找到急了，宝中
Ma?
杂?
-Hi, sweetie. -Ma.
-冬儿子 -妈!
Fluffy, no matter what they say or do, we never stopped believing in you.
不管他们怎订说，我们据你到底
So you'll be back soon, right?
你很快就会回来，对吧?
Hey, come on. Let him eat.
拜旗，让他吃
Go ahead, Dave. Don't mind us.
僵管吃，别管我们
But there's plenty for everyone.
谭该金大家吃的
It’s okay, sugar. We can wait.
没关像，我们可以等
No, no, Ma! Ma!
不， 杂…
There's lots here. Ma!
别走，杂，膛有很多急
Ma!
妈!
-Kids, you gotta see this. -He’s on now.
-孩子们，看看这个 -他来了
Hey! Hello!
味，你好!
-Isn't that the fellow with the wacky feet? -Looks like.
-他不是那个怪脚吐? -好像是那
-What was his name? -l thought he was dead.
-他叫什笨来著? -我以为他死了
-Everybody-- -Apparently not.
-大家… -看来范没有
Everybody, listen up! I’ve got big news.
大家册好，我有大消息
I know who's taking the fish!
我知道是谁抢走急了
-Yeah, and they took his brain. -It’s the aliens.
-他瘦了 -是外星怪客
-l made contact with them. -The lunatic is back.
-外星怪客， 我和他们接角 -小疯子回来了
The aliens are taking our fish.
外星怪客抢走我们的急
Someone ought to fetch Noah and the elders.
快派人去课报诺哈跟长老
Hey, you.
喂，你
Gloria.
萝莉亚
Kind of weird, seeing you again.
又见到你感觉好怪
Yeah.
是啊
-Everything cool here, baby? -You remember Seymour.
-一切都没事吧，宝只 -你记得西摩吧?
Yeah. Hi, Seymour.
记得，，西摩
Yeah.
你好
So which one is yours?
哪个小孩是你的?
All of them.
全部都是
This is our singing class. He teaches rhythm. I teach the blues.
他们是我歌唱班的学生 他教和节奏，我教蓝调
-So you're not--? -l guess I never heard the right song.
-你们没有… -我一直没过到让我心动的对象
That's great! I didn’t mean....
太棒了“，我不是这意思…
I found out who's taking the fish.
我查出是谁偷走了急
They're big and kind of ugly, but, Gloria...
他们很巨大，长得又梗
...the things they can do. They're coming here.
他们很属害，而且要来这壬
Oh, is that so?
真的假的?
They'll be here soon. I think they wanna help us.
他们就快到了“，他们想帮有我们
So now you speak with them?
你跟他们说通话?
Well, they don’t speak penguin, but they seem to respond to this.
他们不会说企鹅话 可是他们对这个有反应
-What’s he doing? -You gotta be kidding me.
-他在堤嘛? -你玩我啊?
I suggest we all do it. It really gets their attention.
我们一起跳会引起他们的注意
And why would it do that?
为什么要这文做?
Beats me, but it works.
我想这样会有用
-Hey, it’s the hippity-hopper. -Freaky feet!
-是那个怪胎 -抽筋黎
Boys, boys--
大彩儿
-Fluffy. -Tall guy.
-大毛球 -大个儿
-Stretch! -Amigo!
-高个! -兄弟
So you dare come back?
你逮敢回来?
He says he’s found aliens and they're taking our fish.
他说外星怪客偷走我们的急
He says that they’re coming and we all have to do this.
他们要来这里，我们要一起跳舞
There be no such thing as aliens!
世上根本就没有外星怪客
Mumble, turn around.
波波，转过去
Is that from them?
是他们和弄的吧?
Yeah. But don’t be afraid. l think it’s a way to find me, that’s all.
对，可是不要怕 这样他们才能找到我
You led them here? You turned them on your own kind?
你带他们来，背叛你的同胞 ?
Wait a second, you just said there’s no such thing as aliens.
等一下 你刚刚才说世上没有外星怪客
Well, there’s not.
是没有啊
But if there were, only a traitorous fool would bring them here.
不过蕊一有 只有叛逢才会带他们来这里
But they have to come.
他们一定要来
They're the ones taking our fish. They can do something about it.
他们偷走我们的急，可以还给我们
None but the Great ’Guin has the power to give and take away.
只有企铭歌神才有这种神力
The Great ’Guin didn’t put things out of whack, the aliens did.
但是企辣歌神没有破壤生秀环境 是外星怪客干的
A fool returns this day to mock our suffering.
这个白病回来嘲笑我们的车准
We are starving and he wants us to hippity-hop.
我们在换钱，他还要我们跳舞
So do we hold fast to our ways...
我们是要坚守企向传统
...or do we bend to the fetid fantasies of a dancing fool?
还是让这个疯狂叛惩思弄我们?
Say, how does that feet thing go again?
你说要怎么跳才对 ?
Yeah, show us, Mumble.
对啊，教我们跳
Oh, it’s really quite easy.
其实很简单
No, no!
不,不!
No, you must resist!
不要匠他的
That's right.
很好
-Pointless nonsense. -Resist! Stand your ground!
-没用处的胡闪 -别匠他的话，芭守立场
Stand your ground against this folly!
抗拒这种胡关的行为
Raise your voices, brothers.
大声吼出来，同胞们
Cry out in defiance of this jiggity-joggity!
发出怒吼来对抗群魔乱舞
Show me what you got.
秀绑招来看看
You got it.
这就对了
Come on.
来吧
Work, work it.
用力跳
Yes, yes! Call on the wisdoms!
很好，召唤智慧之神
Let the world tremble!
让全世界瞧瞧我们的属害
For when all others leave...
大家都秦开，只有我们留守
Mumble! Mumble!
波波
Mama? Amigos.
妈妈，哥们外
-Oh, Mama. -Oh, my boy.
-妈妈 -儿子
-My gorgeous boy. -Oh, Mama.
-我的实贝儿子 -妈妈
-Look at him. -You're so dazzling.
-看看他 -你演得好钟哦
-Oh, Fluffy. -We waited and waited for you.
-大毛球 -我们等了你好久
Believe me. You don't wanna see your deadbeat dad.
你不会想见到你老爸
-Your pa is sort of.... -What?
-你和爸有一点… 一怎样?
Come on, I'll show you.
来，我带你去看他
Memphis?
曼菲斯9?
Pa?
和爸?
Mumble?
波波，真的是你吗?
I thought....
我以为…
Pa?
和爸?
There ain't been one day...
打从你一出生
... not one day, that I done right by you.
我就没有好好对符你
Dance for him, Daddy.
跟他跳舞，跟你儿子一起跳帮
You'll have to forgive me.
你要原谅我
The music's gone clean out of me.
我完全没有和节奏感
No, it hasn't.
薄没有
It’s just like singing with your body.
这就像用身硒唱歌
Come on, baby. We can do it.
来，老公，我们做得到
Oh, Mama.
孩子的杂
It’s just one big old foot after the other.
十焦脚来回跳动就行了
That's it.
这就对了
Yeah.
好耶
-Yeah, see? -Well, that feels good.
-你看吧 ? -感觉好棒
You don’t have to be beautiful
你不一定要很美里
Yeah, Memphis.
很好，曼菲斯
To turn me on
才能迷个我
i just need your body, baby
我只要虹的肉朵，裤中
From dusk till dawn
从早到晚
You don't have to be rich to be my girl
你不必有钱，就是我的女人
You don’t have to be cool To rule my world
你不必要酷，就能撞有我
{just want your extra time and your...
只要给我多点时间和和的…
l think you better dance now.
你最好开始跳舞
First, there was just one. Now there's thousands.
本来只有一焦，现在有疙千焦
-Are they trying to tell us something? -What’s the problem?
-他们想告诉我们什么吗? -问题出在哪?
-We're messing with their food chain. -We've gotta do something.
-我们破壕了他们的食物争 -我们必须设法疆补
-We suggest a ban on all marine harvesting. -Too much money. Too many jobs.
-我建议禁止捕提海洋生物 -竹牲太大了
Why should we do anything at all?
我们为什么要帮他们 ?
They're just a bunch of flightless birds at the bottom of the world.
他们只是一群不会超的策高
I don’t wanna live in a world without penguins.
我不想看到企呜绝种
What are we gonna do about it?
我们应该怎入做?
Bang up the sign "No Fishing.”
立起警示牌，严禁捕急
Is equal to the love...
等蕉你付出的用
Oh, baby. Right on.
裤上中，这就对了
It's like a jungle sometimes
入和委在娄林中
it makes me wonder How I keep from going under
真想就此放素
Bring it on! Go ahead!
跳吧，用力椒吧
Even though we sometimes Would not get a thing
引然不一定能金如磊以借 我们仍是乐在其中，获度佳季
! wish those days Would come back once more
我好希望过去的日子能回来… 为什么过去一去不复返
Come here, babe. Come on back.
让美好的日子回来吧
Come on back
回来吧…回来吧…
1 love them, I love them
我好爱他们… 我党他们，好党好党他们…
IN MEMORY OF IVAN BASTIANICH 1981-2005
(访以此纪念伊凡巴士提亚尼属 1981-2005)
[ENGLISH]
[MANDARIN - R3]